I am an education researcher with over ten years' experience in project coordination and supervision, as well as data management, analysis, and reporting. I am happiest working at the intersection of K-12 education research and data management, helping researchers and practitioners obtain insights that improve student outcomes through harmonized, reliable, and documented data. I am also passionate about helping others organize their data and reporting through reproducible workflows.

# Technical Skills\_

R, SPSS, Qualtrics, Stata, Microsoft Access, Quick Base, SQL, Git and GitHub, Tableau, SAS, SharePoint

# Education

University of Minnesota Minneapolis, MN

MASTER OF PUBLIC POLICY 2009-2011

• Concentration: Advanced Policy Analysis

University of Missouri

Bachelor of Social Work

2001-2005

• Concentration: Research Methods

# **Experience**

#### **Missouri Prevention Science Institute**

University of Missouri

**DIRECTOR OF DATA STRATEGY** 

May 2019 - Present

- Strategize data management plans for over ten actively funded projects and oversee their implementation.
- Merge, clean, manipulate, query, and document data collected from school districts, state education agencies, surveys, assessments, and observations using R.
- Analyze data for publications and build reports and dashboards for partners.

#### DIRECTOR OF RESEARCH IMPLEMENTATION

Jul 2016-May 2019

- Supervised successful completion of data collection activities for six federally funded randomized controlled trial studies and two county funded projects.
- Delivered quarterly trainings to staff on data collection methods.
- Designed Qualtrics surveys and Access tracking databases.

RESEARCH ASSOCIATE Aug 2013 - Jul 2016

- Coordinated two Institute of Education Sciences funded randomized controlled trial studies.
- Collected data in schools through classroom observations, surveys, and assessments.
- Established trusting relationships with school district partners.

### **Big Brothers Big Sisters of Eastern Missouri**

St. Louis, MO

**EVALUATION AND OUTCOMES MANAGER** 

Jun 2011 - Aug 2013

 Oversaw the collection, analysis, and dissemination of data relating to performance management, outcomes, and customer satisfaction.

### **Center for Advanced Studies in Child Welfare**

University of Minnesota

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jan 2010 - Jul 2011

• Evaluated the effectiveness of the Hennepin County Attorney's Office truancy intervention program using qualitative and quantitative methods.

#### **Humphrey School of Public Affairs**

University of Minnesota

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Aug 2010 - Dec 2010

• Taught lab sessions of a graduate level introductory statistics course using Stata.

### **Hennepin-University Partnership**

University of Minnesota

GRADUATE ASSISTANT Sep 2009 - May 2010

· Connected County officials with University faculty to develop effective partnerships to improve the community.

September 2021 1

Service

R-Ladies St. Louis St. Louis, MO

CO-ORGANIZER

Aug 2020 - Present

• Organize and host monthly workshops

LaunchCode St. Louis, MO

TEACHING ASSISTANT

*Jan 2018 - July 2018* 

• Developed curriculum and taught data analysis once a week for a cohort of 25 women looking to make a career transition.

### **AmeriCorps St. Louis Education Team**

St. Louis, MO

TEAM LEAD

Aug 2007 - Aug 2008

• Tutored elementary students, led educational programming, and supervised a team of three tutors

# **Publications**

Henry, L., Reinke, W.M., Herman, K.C., Thompson, A.M. & Lewis, C.G. (2020) Motivational interviewing with at-risk students (MARS) mentoring: Addressing the unique mental health needs of students in alternative school placements, School Psychology Review, Advance online publication.

Huang, F., Lewis, C., Cohen, D., Prewett, S., & Herman, K. (2018). Bullying involvement, teacher-student relationships, and psychosocial outcomes. School Psychology Quarterly, 33(2), 223-234.

Lewis, C.G., Herman, K.C., Huang, F.L., Stormont, M., Grossman, C., Eddy, C., & Reinke, W.M. (2017). The utility of single-item readiness screeners in middle school. Journal of School Psychology. 64, 1–16.

Larson, A., Singh, S. & Lewis, C. (2011). Sanctions and Education Outcomes for Children in TANF Families, Child and Youth Services, 32:3, 180-199.

# **Presentations**

Lewis, C. (2021). Data Management in Large-Scale Education Research. Series of workshops given for Missouri Prevention Science Institute, University of Missouri, Columbia, MO.

Lewis, C. (2019). Cleaning Messy Data in R. Presented at R-Ladies St. Louis Meetup, Washington University in St. Louis.

Lewis, C. (2019). Introduction to R. Guest lecture for LaunchCode CoderGirl Data Analysis track, St. Louis, MO.

Lewis, C. (2018). Survey Says: You can use Tableau to Impact School Climate. Presented at Tableau Fringe Festival APAC, Online.

September 2021 2